##The First Restoration

<img src="lastgroup.jpg" width="300" height="275" alt="" class="right">In 1997 the D'ni Restoration Council formed and the restoration of D'ni officially started. The DRC was making huge progress, but in 2004 the DRC lost funding and had to close the cavern.

*	[Timeline](timeline/)
*	[Sights & Sounds](sights-and-sounds/)
*	[Age Notes](age-notes/)
*	Contests

##The Second Restoration

Late 2006 the restoration continued with Cate Alexander funding the DRC. However, late 2007 Cate Alexander stopped funding the restoration, saying that she didn't get sufficient returns on her investments.

*	[Project List](project-list/)
*	Explorer Contributions
	*	[Explorer Restoration Projects](explorers/)
	*	[Stained Glass Windows](stained-glass/)
	*	[Feed the Lake Algae Project](lake-algae/)
	*	D'ni Language Project
