#### History

Guild Master wrote his own Age sometime fairly close to the Fall, presumably in the mid 9390's.

#### Synopsis

The age Kadish Tolesa was rightly named after its creator Guild Master Kadish. Guild Master Kadish was a very experienced writer and engineer whose influence was far reaching in the creations of the D'ni in their last days. His unique style is most plainly seen in this personal Age of the Guild Master.

More documents are being translated at this time.

#### DRC Notes

Kadish- 12/2000- Phase 1 inspections complete - Passed    
Initial Mapping Complete - Sutherland    
Architectural Analysis Complete - Not Approved - 02/2001 - Engberg    
Architectural Analysis Complete - Approved - 11/2001 - Engberg    
Phase Five Approval - Sutherland 
