Explorers,

The cleanup of the damaged building is still in progress, but the remaining structure does not show signs of another collapse. Our investigation into the cause of the collapse and the remainder of the cleanup will likely last for several weeks. In the meantime, however, we are reopening the alley to the Kahlo Pub with the understanding that the area should still be considered hazardous. Enter that alley at your own risk.

The DRC
