Explorers,

Many of you know that I've been working closely with the DRC for many months now, though I haven't been officially been a member of the Council itself. With Michael Engberg still missing, the time has come for my role with the Council to increase.

The remaining Council members have graciously elected to have me join them in an official capacity.

I am very pleased to help the Council through this difficult time in any way that I can.

Cate
