Explorers,

As many of you have already heard, Cate Alexander unexpectedly resigned earlier today, citing that the Restoration effort is not giving her sufficient return on her investment to justify continuing her investment. The remaining DRC members are in the process of of determining what our course of action in the weeks and months ahead will be in the light of this recent development. We will keep you informed as decisions in this matter are made.

Thank you for your understanding,

The DRC
