The DRC is proud to announce the release of Eder Delin. You will notice the book is not in every neighborhood. We must insist that you don't start new neighborhoods just to find one with a Book. The next Age will placed in neighborhoods that don't have an Eder Delin book.

Feel free to find a public neighborhood or a friend that does have Eder Delin. We'll have the next Age out as soon as possible.

The DRC
