The DRC is proud to announce the opening of miniature Guild Halls. In order to continue our effort at a full restoration of the Guilds, the DRC is releasing five areas that will be designated Guild Halls. Only supporters of each Guild (those who own that Guild's T-shirt) will be allowed access to the respective Guild Hall.

We have much larger plans for the Guilds but, again, every step forward is a step in the right direction and we are pleased to take another large step toward our goals.

Thank you,

The DRC
