Explorers,

For those who have been asking for ways to contribute to the restoration, another project has now become available to the Explorers: the calibration of the Great Zero.

If you are interested in contributing to this project, please visit the Great Zero Antechamber (via one of the linking books in your neighborhood) and read the DRC journal there for details of this project.

Thank you,
Victor Laxman
