Explorers,

The DRC has always been excited to return the Guilds to the Cavern and today marks a special day in that effort. We are proud to announce the opening of Kirel: The Guild Neighborhood. Though it is a small step, it is a step in the right direction.

We invite you to visit the neighborhood, learn of the five Guilds represented, and envision a future when all the Guilds are active once again and how you may choose to be a part of that.

The DRC
