I would like to take another opportunity to thank all of the explorers for continuing to contribute pellets to the lake. I have been monitoring the pellet contributions on a daily basis and have noticed that they've been steadily decreasing over the last month. I just wanted to reassure you that you are making a progress, so don't get discouraged. At the current rate of pellet contributions, the increased lake light level could be enough to be noticeable in the next few months. Of course, if they continue to decline, it will take a great deal longer.

Also, according to our tests, the algae does not respond well to spikes in their food supply. Slow and steady is better than large, sudden changes in the pellet contributions. The D'ni do have several safety mechanisms in place to moderate this to some degree, so the algae isn't in any great danger, but for our own efficiency's sake, it's better to be as consistent as is reasonable.

Thanks again,

V. Laxman
