Dear Explorers,

As some of you have discovered, a small crack has appeared of the north wall of the alley near the public city's Kahlo pub. The most recent studies of that building has shown it to be stable, but it appears that that may no longer be the case. We do not have an explanation for this new crack, and we will be reevaluating the condition of the building to the north of the Kahlo Pub in the days ahead.

In the meantime, we ask that you consider this area to be dangerous and limit your explorations to other areas of the city.

Thank you,

The DRC
