Took the throne in 2356 DE at the age of 86. Naygen did much to encourage the growth of the Major Guild of Fine Artists, as well as the seeking of the other "truths". The year 2500 DE (1000 years after the death of the Great King) would mark the peak of what some would call "the religious confusion"[^1]. There were over 2000 registered sects and the original beliefs of Ri'neref were known by very few. Naygen was clearly not one of them.

It is 2397 DE that most officially marks the start of the D'ni Renaissance. In that year, the Eamis Theatre Company hosted the first play written by the playwright Sirreh. The play dealt with the Pento War and the Great King himself and was one which Naygen praised. It ended up being sold out for three straight weeks and marked not only the start of theatre as a popular entertainment source within the culture, but also the beginning of the Pento War subject, which would go on to become one of the most dealt with topics of their history in their Art. 

In 2408 DE, the 33-year-old musician Airem began selling out concert halls, marking the beginning of yet another career of one of the great D'ni artists. His music also dealt much with the Great King, many times ridiculing him. Naygen praised his people for being able to express "their true feelings in such wonderful displays of art"[^2].

In 2488 DE, the first successful extrusion tests were carried out by the Guild of Miners, and to great applause from the public. Naygen used the occasion to "benefit everyone". He appointed the Guild of Miners as a Major Guild replacing the Guild of Fine Artists. He then split the Guild of Fine Artists up into the Minor Guilds of Sculptors, Artists, Actors, and Musicians. The split was to encourage growth in mining as well as the arts, two major causes of Naygen throughout his reign. His proposal was strongly supported by Sirreh and Airem, as well as other artists, who viewed it as an excellent opportunity for the growth of their respective fields. 

In 2500 DE, Naygen proposed the construction of a new Council chamber for the Guilds. Somewhat surprising, was that he suggested it should be built over the Tomb of the Great King. The proposal was met with little opposition[^3], and construction began two years later. In 2502 DE, the Tomb of the Great King was barely visible, a tremendous symbol of what D'ni had become. 

Later it was discovered that within the Council chamber was a massive vault, protected by "puzzles" of a sort. The tomb had always been known for its patterns, some of which were claimed to have prophetic messages. Naygen apparently became enamored with the patterns and spread them throughout the unseen portions of the chamber as well as the seen. Though the public knew very little of the vault at the time of construction, years later, it was found to contain a tremendous amount of royal wealth, something Naygen often publicly encouraged. Of course, most were not able to save the amounts Naygen did, but still the idea of saving one's money for future generations was strongly encouraged by him.   

Naygen died in 2533 DE at the age of 263 leaving the throne to his third son. In memorial to Naygen, Sirreh wrote another of the more popular of his plays entitled "Our Great King". It was the first play performed by the Minor Guild of Actors in 2535 DE.


[^1]: Taken from the journal of Tevahr in 3075

[^2]: From a speech by Naygen, christening the Minor Guild of Musicians

[^3]: Though the official Church registered a complaint, it seemed there was little heart behind it. Apparently, even a prophetess of Naygen supported the proposition
